<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 17:37:41 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 17:37:41 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roasted Squash and Arugula Salad</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup pecans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Neutral oil such as olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1-2 pound butternut squash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 pound chicken breast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup slivered shallots&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons sherry vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7-ounce bag arugula&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;several sprigs fresh thyme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8-ounce package goat’s cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 375°F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Toss the pecans with a little canola oil and sea salt, and roast until fragrant, about 7 to 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, peel and seed the squash and cut into 1/2-inch cubes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Toss with a little canola oil on two baking sheets (do not crowd) and sprinkle with more of the sea salt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When the pecans are done, remove from the oven, raise the temperature to 425°F and roast the squash until it’s soft and the edges are deep brown.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While the squash roasts, cut the chicken into 1-inch cubes and fry it up in a large skillet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep the pan hot and add 6 tablespoons oil to the pan. Add the shallots and saute over medium heat until they soften.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn off the heat and add the vinegar. Swirl to combine. Add a few turns of the pepper mill’s worth of fresh black pepper.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The salad can be served now, with the ingredients still warm, or at room temperature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To assemble:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large bowl, toss the dressing with the squash and chicken.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add several large handfuls of the arugula.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strip about three or four sprigs of thyme leaves into the bowl and add the pecans (which should be broken into pieces if they’re not already.) Toss gently.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dot with the goat cheese (you may not need all of it) and serve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/arugula-squash-salad.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/arugula-squash-salad.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sweet Potato Rolls</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/4 cup (6 ounces) warm water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 scant tablespoon (1 package) active dry yeast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup (9 ounces) mashed sweet potatoes (see Recipe Notes below)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup (8.5 ounces) milk, whole or 2% preferably&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup (2 ounces) unsalted butter, melted&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons light brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 cups (20 ounces) all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine the water and yeast in a large mixing bowl and let stand until the yeast is dissolved.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the mashed sweet potatoes, the milk, the melted butter, the brown sugar, and the salt. Stir until all ingredients are evenly combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the flour, stirring until a shaggy dough is formed and no more dry flour is visible. This dough will be very sticky.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover with plastic wrap or a clean kitchen towel and let stand until doubled in bulk, at least 2 hours or as long as 5 hours. The dough can be used immediately, but it’s easier to work with if you can refrigerate it for at least 2 hours. The dough can also be refrigerated for up to 24 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When ready to shape the rolls, sprinkle your work surface with a little flour and turn the dough out on top.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sprinkle a little more flour on top and press the dough into a thick disk.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a bench scraper or knife to divide the dough into 24 pieces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shape into balls and place about 5 inches apart on a parchment-lined baking sheet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover and allow to rise until the rolls are roughly doubled in size, about 45 minutes in a warm kitchen.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;About 20 minutes before the rolls are finished rising, preheat the oven to 400°F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove the cover and bake the rolls for 20 to 25 minutes, until they are puffed and toasted-brown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve warm or room temperature. Rolls are best the first day, but will stay fresh for several days after if stored in an airtight container.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recipe Notes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To make the mashed sweet potatoes, roast a medium-sized (roughly 9-ounce) sweet potato in a 400°F oven until completely soft. Strip off the skin and mash.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For extra richness, brush the tops with melted butter or egg yolk before baking. So good!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These rolls can also be frozen if you’re making them ahead of time. Allow the baked rolls to cool completely, wrap them in aluminum foil, and freeze them. To reheat, let them thaw on the counter and then warm them in a 300°F oven for 15 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/sweet-potato-rolls.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sweet-potato-rolls.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Masala Chai Tea</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/4 cup water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2-4 whole green cardamom pods, smashed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1-2 thin slices fresh ginger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1-inch cinnamon stick&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 piece star anise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/4 cup milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2 teaspoons loose black tea leaves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sweetener, to taste (I prefer honey or maple syrup)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a small saucepan, combine the water, cardamom, ginger, cinnamon stick and star anise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring the mixture to a boil then lower the heat and simmer for a few minutes until the mixture is fragrant.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the milk and tea leaves, and simmer for another minute then turn off the heat and let steep for 2 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour into a cup through a fine mesh sieve. Discard the leaves and spices. Add sweetener, to taste.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/masala-chai-tea.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/masala-chai-tea.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cinnamon Swirl Bread</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup (8 oz) warm water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon active dry yeast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup (8 oz) milk, whole, 2%, or skim&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup (2 oz) unsalted butter, melted&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;51/2 - 6 cups (1 lb 11.5 oz - 1 lb 14 oz) all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;filling&quot;&gt;Filling:&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup granulated white sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2 tablespoons cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large egg beaten with 2 teaspoons warm water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour a cup of 70°-80° water into the bowl of a standing mixer or large mixing bowl. Sprinkle the yeast over top. Give it a few minutes, then stir to fully dissolve the yeast into the water.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stir the milk, melted butter, and salt into the water.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add 51/2 cups of the flour and stir to form a shaggy dough.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Knead in your mixer on low speed with a dough hook or knead by hand for 8-10 minutes to form a smooth, slightly tacky dough.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check the dough halfway through; if it’s very sticky (think: bubble gum), add a little more flour. The dough is ready when it forms a ball without sagging and quickly springs back when poked.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Toss a few tablespoons of flour to absorb any residual moisture from when they were plumped. With the mixer on gradually add them to the bowl and continue kneading until they are evenly distributed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If kneading by hand, turn the dough out onto your work surface and pat it into an oval. Fold the dough like a letter. Pat it into an oval again and fold it again. Knead the dough by hand for a few minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Return the dough to the bowl and cover. Let the dough rise in a warm place until doubled in bulk, about an hour.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, combine the sugar and cinnamon in a small bowl and beat together the egg and water in a second bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Divide the dough into two pieces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Working with one piece at a time, roll the dough out on the counter. It should be slightly less wide than your baking pan and as long as you can make it. The thinner the dough, the more layers of crazy-good cinnamon swirl you’ll end up with. If the dough starts to shrink back on you, let it rest for a few minutes and then try again.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brush the entire surface of the dough with egg wash, leaving about two inches clear at the top. Sprinkle generously with cinnamon and sugar.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Starting at the end closest to you, roll up the dough. When you get to the top, pinch the seam closed. Transfer the loaf to your loaf pan seam-side down. Repeat with the other half of the dough.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let the loaves rise until mounded over the top of the pan and pillowy, 30-40 minutes. Halfway through rising, preheat the oven to 375° F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brush the top with some of the remaining egg wash. If desired, sprinkle some of your remaining cinnamon-sugar over the tops of the loaves as well. Bake for 40-45 minutes until golden brown.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove the loaves from the pans and allow them to cool completely before slicing. Baked loaves can also be frozen for up to three months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/cinnamon-swirl-bread.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/cinnamon-swirl-bread.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chai Apple Cider</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 cups apple cider&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1-inch whole piece ginger, peeled&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 whole cinnamon stick&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8 whole cloves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 whole cardamom pods&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 whole black peppercorns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 whole star anise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 whole vanilla bean, sliced in half lengthwise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup whipped cream (store-bought or homemade)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon maple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ground cinnamon, for topping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a 2-quart sauce pan, combine the apple cider with the ginger, cinnamon, cloves, cardamom pods, peppercorns, star anise, and vanilla bean. Bring mixture to a boil, then reduce to a simmer. Let simmer for 15 minutes until fragrant.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strain the cider and divide between two mugs. Fold the maple syrup into the whipped cream, then dollop it into each mug. Finish with a sprinkle of cinnamon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/chai-apple-cider.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/chai-apple-cider.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Acorn Squash Soup</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 acorn squash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 onion, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/4 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp smoked paprika&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 tsp allspice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 tsp cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/8 tsp nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/8 tsp cayenne pepper, optional&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 cups broth (I like chicken)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup cream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To prepare the squash poke all over with a fork and microwave until softened, about 4-5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow to cool and scoop out flesh, discard seeds and rind.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat butter over medium-low heat in a large pot.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add onion and cook until softened, about 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add spices and salt, cook for 30 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add squash and broth. Turn up heat to high and bring to a boil.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover, reduce heat to low and simmer for 10-12 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Puree with an immersion blender or in batches in a blender. Stir in cream and serve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/acorn-squash-soup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/acorn-squash-soup.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pumpkin Spice Latte</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;That’s right, we’re going there. It’s officially fall, and for those who like me don’t want to consume &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;50+ grams of sugar&lt;/a&gt; you can make your own PSL at home!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons canned pumpkin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon pumpkin pie spice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon maple syrup (or sweetener of choice. Sugar, honey, agave, dates, all work!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup milk of choice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 to 2 shots espresso, about 1/4 cup, or 8 oz extra strong coffee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon coconut oil (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whipped cream (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heat the pumpkin and spices&lt;/strong&gt;: I like to do this by mixing the pumpkin and spices in a small microwave safe bowl and microwaving for 1 minute. You can also do it in a saucepan on the stove.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stir in the sugar&lt;/strong&gt;: Add the sugar and stir until the mixture looks like a bubbly thick syrup.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warm the milk&lt;/strong&gt;: I usually just heat the milk in it’s own saucepan. You can also mix it into the pumpkin and spices if you’re already using a saucepan for that.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blend&lt;/strong&gt;: Add everything to a blender and blend on medium-low for 1-2 minutes, until the mixture is frothy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve! Top with whipped cream and extra spices if you’d like, or just enjoy as-is.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/pumpkin-spice-latte.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/pumpkin-spice-latte.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>drinks</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apple Pull-Apart Bread</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;for-the-dough&quot;&gt;For the Dough:&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 ¼ teaspoon (1 package) active dry yeast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup warm water, about 105° to 155° F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;big pinch of sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 tablespoons granulated sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup (1½ sticks) unsalted butter, at room temperature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon ground cardamom&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 large eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4½ to 5 cups all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup warm whole milk, 105° to 115° F.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;for-the-filling&quot;&gt;For the Filling:&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 large apples, peeled and cut into small cubes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons fresh lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon ground cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon fresh ground nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pinch of salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;for-the-streusel&quot;&gt;For the Streusel:&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pinch of salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pinch of cardamom&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons unsalted butter, at room temperature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 egg and sugar for brushing and topping the dough before baking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;to-make-the-dough&quot;&gt;To Make the Dough&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a small bowl, mix together yeast, warm water and pinch of sugar.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stir together until yeast is dissolved and set aside for 10 minutes. Yeast will foam up, that’s how you know it’s alive!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the bowl of an electric stand mixer fitted with a paddle attachment, add
the sugar, butter, cardamom, and salt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blend on medium speed until pale in color and fluffy, about 3 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stop the mixer, scrape down the bowl, and add eggs and 1 cup of flour.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blend on medium speed until thoroughly incorporated and creamy, about 1 minute.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stop the mixer and add 2 cups more cups of flour, foamy yeast mixture, and warm
milk.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blend in medium speed until the flour disappears.  Mixture will be very wet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add 1½ to 2 more cups of flour.  Blend until the flour is almost incorporated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dump the dough onto a lightly floured work surface.  Knead for 5 to 8 minutes
by hand.  Dough will be glossy and just slightly sticky.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place dough in an oiled bowl, cover with plastic wrap and a towel and let rest in a warm place
for 1½ hours, or until doubled in size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the dough rises, make the apple filling and the streusel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;to-make-the-apple-filling&quot;&gt;To make the Apple Filling&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Toss together diced apples, lemon juice, sugar, cinnamon, cornstarch, nutmeg and salt.  Leave at room temperature and set aside
until ready to use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;to-make-the-streusel-filling&quot;&gt;To make the Streusel Filling&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a small bowl, whisk together flour, sugar, cinnamon, salt, and cardamom.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add butter and, using your fingers, work the butter into the flour mixture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Break up the butter into the mixture, until thoroughly incorporated and
crumbly.  Set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;assemble-and-bake&quot;&gt;Assemble and Bake&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Line two baking sheets with parchment paper and set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When the dough has doubled in size, dump it out onto a lightly floured work
surface.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a large knife or a bench knife to divide the dough in two.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roll each dough piece into about a 10×14-inch rectangle.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sprinkle with half of the streusel mixture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add half of the apple mixture over the streusel. Add a bit of the apple juices too!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Starting from the longest side, begin to roll the dough.  This isn’t like a
cinnamon roll, you don’t have to roll it into a super tight swirl.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fold in about 1½ to 1-inch folds.  Keep the seam on the bottom.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Repeat the same steps for the second piece of dough.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carefully lift roll onto the prepared baking sheet. &lt;strong&gt;Now is a great time to
freeze or refrigerate the coffee cake  dough for later baking.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take a pair of clean scissors and slice into the dough leaving about ¾-inch of dough
still attached.  Slice at 1-inch intervals.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carefully begin to curve the sliced dough into a semi-circle/horseshoe shape.  If some of the apple juices
escape, that’s ok&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover with a towel and let rest in a warm place for 30 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat the oven to 375° F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brush dough with egg wash and sprinkle with raw or granulated sugar.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 30 to 35 minutes, until golden brown and cooked through.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove from the oven, allow to cool for 15 minutes before serving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best served warm with hot coffee.  Coffee cake will last, well wrapped at room temperature, for up to 3 days… or 3 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you decide to freeze the dough, place it in the fridge to thaw the
evening before you’d like to bake it.  Once it’s thawed, slice it according to
the above directions.  Allow to come to room temperature, and allow to rise for
another 30 minutes beyond that.  Wash with egg and sugar, then bake.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you decide to refrigerate the dough, simple take it out of the fridge,
slice according to the above directions.  Let come to room temperature, then
allow to rise for 30 minutes beyond that.  Brush with egg and sugar, then bake.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/apple-pull-apart-bread.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/apple-pull-apart-bread.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pumpkin Pancakes</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup whole wheat flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 Tablespoons brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons baking powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ teaspoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ teaspoon ground cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ teaspoon fresh grated nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pinch of ground ginger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pinch of ground cloves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup canned pumpkin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 egg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 Tablespoons vegetable oil or melted butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whisk together flours, salt, spices, sugar and baking powder in a medium sized bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a separate bowl, whisk together milk, egg, pumpkin and vegetable oil or melted butter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour the wet ingredients into the dry ingredients and whisk until just combined.  Don’t worry if you have a few lumps.  You don’t want to over beat the batter, it’ll produce tough pancakes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let the batter sit for 10 minutes while you heat the skillet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Over low-medium heat melt a tablespoon of butter or vegetable oil. Once skillet is hot, spoon a heaping 2 tablespoons of batter per pancake into the skillet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When pancake starts to bubble slightly, carefully flip over.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once browned and cooked through place pancakes on a plate. Enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tip&lt;/strong&gt;: While you’re cooking the rest of the pancakes, we generally heat the over to it’s lowest temperature and put the pancakes on an oven-proof plate, and keep them in there to stay warm&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/pumpkin-pancakes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/pumpkin-pancakes.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>breakfasts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cinnamon Rolls</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;for-the-rolls&quot;&gt;For the Rolls&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup lukewarm milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large egg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large egg yolk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup (8 tablespoons) unsalted butter, softened&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 cups King Arthur Unbleached All-Purpose Flour, plus more for dusting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 ¼ teaspoons Red Star Platinum, Active Dry or Quick Rise yeast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons light brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ teaspoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;for-the-filling&quot;&gt;For the Filling&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup finely chopped walnuts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup finely chopped pecans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅓ cup unsalted butter, softened&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup brown sugar, packed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons ground cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8 ounces cream cheese, softened and divided (3 tablespoons set aside for the icing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;for-the-icing&quot;&gt;For the Icing&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;remaining 3 tablespoons of softened cream cheese&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup confectioners’ sugar or glazing sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ½ tablespoons milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;to-make-the-dough&quot;&gt;To make the dough&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place all of the dough ingredients in the bowl of a stand mixer fitted with a dough hook, and gently mix together with a spatula before fitting the bowl into the mixer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix on low until the dough begins to come together. The dough will come together into a soft, though not too sticky dough ball after several minutes of hand mixing and stand mixer mixing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the dough in a lightly greased bowl and lightly dust the top of the dough with flour. The flour will help you see that the dough is rising.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let it rise until it’s almost double in size, about 2 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;to-make-the-filling&quot;&gt;To make the filling&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine the nuts in one bowl, and the butter, brown sugar, and ground cinnamon in another. Set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;assembling&quot;&gt;Assembling&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On a lightly floured work surface, roll the dough into a 14 x 12 inch rectangle.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spread the softened cream cheese evenly over the surface and fold the bottom and top edges of the dough over 1 inch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fold one short end into the center. Fold the other short end over the first, like you were folding a letter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carefully roll the dough into a 14 x 12 inch rectangle again, being careful not to tear the dough and reveal the cream cheese. Fold it like a letter again.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finally, roll the dough into a 12 x 18 inch rectangle. If some cream cheese starts to come through the dough, just flour the dough slightly and keep moving along.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spread the cinnamon filling evenly over the dough, followed by the nuts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beginning with one long edge, roll the dough into a log.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut the log into 8 or 9 equal slices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the slices in a greased 9 inch square or 10 inch square baking pan, cover with plastic wrap, and let rise for 1 hour more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Towards the end of the rising time, preheat the oven to 375°F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake the rolls for 30 to 35 minutes, until they’re golden brown. Remove the rolls from the oven.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;to-ice&quot;&gt;To ice&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whisk together the remaining cream cheese and sugar. Add the milk and whisk. Drizzle icing over the warm buns, and enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes&lt;/strong&gt;: To make the rolls the night before follow the recipe through
slicing the rolls and placing them in the greased baking dish. Instead of
leaving them out to rise, cover with plastic and place the rolls in the
refrigerator to slowly rise overnight. When you want to bake them the next
day, allow them to come to room temperature on the kitchen counter for about
30 minutes, preheat the oven and bake according to the recipe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/cinnamon-rolls.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/cinnamon-rolls.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
