<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:57:39 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:57:39 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Broccoli Quinoa</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 cups cooked quinoa&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 cups raw broccoli, cut into small florets and stems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 medium garlic cloves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup sliced or slivered almonds, toasted&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅓ cup freshly grated Parmesan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 big pinches salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons fresh lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup coconut milk, heavy cream, or cashew cream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Optional toppings: slivered basil, sliced avocado, crumbled feta or goat cheese, more slivered almonds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat the quinoa and set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now barely cook the broccoli by pouring ¾ cup water into a large pot and bringing it to a simmer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add a big pinch of salt and stir in the broccoli.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover and cook for a minute, just long enough to take the raw edge off.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer the broccoli to a strainer. Set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To make the broccoli pesto, puree two cups of the cooked broccoli, the garlic, almonds, Parmesan, salt, and lemon juice in a food processor. Drizzle in the olive oil and cream and pulse until smooth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Just before serving, toss the quinoa and remaining broccoli florets with about ½ of the broccoli pesto. Taste and adjust if needed, you might want to add more of the pesto a bit at a time, or you might want a bit more salt or an added squeeze of lemon juice. Top with toppings and serve!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/broccoli-quinoa.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/broccoli-quinoa.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Instant Pot Chickpea Vegetable Soup with Parmesan</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 whole clove&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 medium onion, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 pound dried chickpeas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons rosemary, divided&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 garlic cloves, minced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablspoons extra virgin olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8 cups vegetable or chicken broth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 small Parmesan rind, plus 1/2 cup freshly grated Parmesan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 28oz can diced tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 medium carrots, sliced into 1/4-inch rounds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 celery stalks, sliced 1/4-inch thick&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zest of 1 lemon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ teaspoon black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the clove, onion, chickpeas, 1 teaspoon of rosemary, garlic, olive oil, cheese rind, and broth into the instant pot liner.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set the timer to 35 minutes on high pressure.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let off the steam.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn on the saute function, and add the tomatoes, carrots and celery, cover loosely, and simmer until the vegetables are soft, about 25 minutes longer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While soup simmers, mix the chopped rosemary, grated Parmesan, lemon zest and pepper in a small bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Season the soup to taste and ladle into bowls. Sprinkle with the Parmesan mixture.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/chickpea-vegetable-soup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/chickpea-vegetable-soup.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>soups</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Miso Peanut Butter Cookies</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1¼ cups whole wheat flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ tsp baking soda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10 tbsp unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup (packed) dark brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large egg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅓ cup smooth almond butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup miso&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup bittersweet chocolate chips or wafers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place racks in upper and lower thirds of oven; preheat to 350°F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whisk flour and baking soda in a medium bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Melt butter in a small saucepan over medium heat, swirling occasionally, until it foams then browns, 5–6 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer to a medium bowl and let cool 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add brown sugar and stir until well combined, about 1 minute.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add egg and continue to stir until mixture is smooth, about 1 minute longer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add almond butter, miso, and vanilla and stir until well combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix in dry ingredients, scraping down sides of bowl as needed, until combined. Let the dough rest 10 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scoop 2-tablespoonfuls of dough and roll into a ball (you should have 16 balls).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arrange on 2 parchment-lined baking sheets, spacing 2” apart.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a crosshatch pattern with a fork across tops of dough (if fork sticks to dough, dip into water before continuing).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake cookies, rotating sheets halfway through, until lightly browned and firm around the edges, 12–14 minutes. Let cool.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Melt chocolate in a microwave in 20-second blasts, stirring in between, until completely smooth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dip 1 side of each cookie into chocolate and return to baking sheets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let sit at room temperature until chocolate hardens, about 2 hours, then enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/miso-peanut-butter-cookies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/miso-peanut-butter-cookies.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>desserts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ombre Rainbow Cookies</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nonstick vegetable oil spray&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1½ cups (3 sticks) unsalted butter, room temperature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1½ cups sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10 ounces almond paste (about 1 cup), crumbled&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons vegetable oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ teaspoon kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 large eggs, room temperature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 cups all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5¾ teaspoons plus 4 drops green or red food coloring, divided&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 teaspoons matcha (green tea powder) or 1 ounce (about 1 cup) freeze-dried raspberries, divided&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup jam, divided&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place racks in upper and lower thirds of oven and preheat to 350°F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lightly coat three 13x9” baking dishes with nonstick spray and line with parchment paper, leaving overhang on both long sides.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using an electric mixer on high speed, beat butter, sugar, almond paste, oil, and salt in a large bowl until mixture is well combined and fluffy, 5–8 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add eggs, one at a time, beating after each addition to incorporate before adding the next.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue to beat mixture until pale and fluffy, about 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reduce speed to low and, with motor running, gradually add flour. Continue mixing just until combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Divide batter evenly among 3 bowls. (Scoop out about ⅔ cups per bowl, or weigh out 160 g batter for each.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If making matcha cookies, mix 4 drops green food coloring and ½ tsp matcha into batter in first bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix ¾ tsp green food coloring and 1½ tsp matcha to batter in second bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix 5 tsp green food coloring and 3 tsp matcha into batter in last bowl. (This will create three shades of green batter.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scrape a bowl of batter into each prepared pan and smooth tops.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake cakes, rotating pans halfway through, until center springs back when gently pressed, 12–15 minutes. Let cakes cool completely in pans.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove lightest-colored cake from pan, turning out onto a surface, and carefully peel away parchment paper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spread half of jam evenly over top.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove medium-colored cake from pan, peel away parchment paper, and place on top of light cake. Spread evenly with remaining jam.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove darkest-colored cake from its pan, peel away parchment paper, and place on top.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Press down gently to adhere layers and wrap tightly in plastic; chill at least 1 hour.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To make cookies, trim edges to square off; about ½” on each side should do it. Then, using a serrated knife, cut cake crosswise into 1½”-wide strips (you should have 8 total). Cut strips crosswise into ¾”-thick pieces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/ombre-cookies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/ombre-cookies.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Instant Pot Cioppino</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons vegetable oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;28 oz can diced tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup diced onion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup chopped carrots&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup broth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons minced garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons ground fennel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon dried oregano&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon red pepper flakes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 cups mixed seafood such as fish chunks, shrimp, bay scallops, mussels and calamari rings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1-2 tablespoons fresh lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place oil, tomato, onions, carrots, water, broth, tomato paste, garlic, oregano, ground fennel seeds, salt and pepper into the inner liner of the Instant pot. Stir well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set Instant Pot at High pressure for 15 minutes. When cook time is complete, let pot sit undisturbed for 10 minutes, and then release any remaining pressure. You can complete these steps and put the soup away in the refrigerator, to finish later. This really helps the flavors in the soup develop, but if you’re ready to eat, it’s not necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn the pot to sauté and add fish, mussels, bay scallops, and calamari rings to the pot. Once the pot boils, add in the shrimp and cook until all the seafood is cooked through. Add lemon juice right before serving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/cioppino.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/cioppino.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>soups</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Matcha Cookies</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ stick butter, softened&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup of granulated sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ teaspoon vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 egg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup + 1 teaspoon all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon culinary grade matcha powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon baking powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pinch of salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cream together the butter and sugar with an electric mixer - it should be creamy colored and airy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gently incorporate the egg to the butter mixture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a separate bowl, sift together all the dry ingredients.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the dry ingredients to the wet by adding a little at a time and folding or gently mixing the batter together. Keep going until you’ve incorporated all the remaining flour mixture. The dough should be a beautiful green color.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chill the dough for at least an hour - up to overnight. The longer the better!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat your oven to 325°F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roll the dough into balls the size of ping pong balls and place them on a non-stick cookie sheet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake them for 12-15 minutes until the bottoms just start to become golden brown and the cookie no longer looks wet in the middle.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove and let cool on a rack and enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/matcha-cookies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/matcha-cookies.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>desserts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Citrus Poppyseed Cookies</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2¼ cups-all purpose flour
¼ cup cornmeal
2 tablespoons poppy seeds
½ teaspoon baking soda
¼ teaspoon sea salt
½ cup unsalted butter, at room temp
1 cup sugar, more for sprinkling
1½ teaspoons lemon zest
1½ teaspoons orange zest
¼ cup extra-virgin olive oil
1 large egg
2 tablespoons lemon juice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/citrus-poppyseed-cookies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/citrus-poppyseed-cookies.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pumpkin Challah</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;challah-ingredients&quot;&gt;Challah Ingredients&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 packages active dry yeast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;125 ml lukewarm water, divided&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1.5 tbsp white sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;0.5 large egg (white and yolk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 large egg yolks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;42.38 g honey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tbsp canola oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ tsp nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ tsp allspice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ tsp ginger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pinch cloves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;55 g brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;245 g pumpkin puree (homemade or canned)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;476 g all-purpose baking flour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;egg-wash-ingredients&quot;&gt;Egg Wash Ingredients&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large egg yolk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;0.5 tbsp water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour 100 ml of the lukewarm water (about 110°F) into a large mixing bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add packet of yeast and 1 tsp of sugar to the bowl, stir to dissolve.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wait 10 minutes. The yeast should have activated, meaning it will look expanded and foamy. If it doesn’t, your yeast may have expired, which means your bread won’t rise—go buy some fresh yeast!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once your yeast has activated, add remaining lukewarm water to the bowl along with the rest of the sugar, egg, egg yolks, honey, canola oil, salt and spices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a whisk to thoroughly blend the ingredients together.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whisk in the brown sugar and pumpkin puree to form a thick liquid.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Begin adding the flour to the bowl by half-cupfuls, stirring with a large spoon each time flour is added. When mixture becomes too thick to stir, use your hands to knead.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue to add flour and knead the dough until it’s smooth, elastic, and not sticky. The amount of flour you will need to achieve this texture varies—only add flour until the dough feels pliable and “right.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place a saucepan full of water on the stove to boil.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, remove the dough from your mixing bowl and wash out the bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grease the bowl with canola oil. Push the dough back into the bottom of the bowl, then flip it over so that both sides are slightly moistened by the oil.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover the bowl with a clean, damp kitchen towel. Place the bowl of dough on the middle rack of your oven.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take the saucepan full of boiling water and place it below the rack where your dough sits.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Close the oven, but do not turn it on. The pan of hot water will create a warm, moist environment for your dough to rise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let the dough rise for 1 hour.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take the dough bowl out and punch it down several times to remove air pockets.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place it back inside the oven and let it rise for 1 hour longer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take the dough out of the oven. Flour a smooth surface like a cutting board.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Punch the dough down into the bowl a few times, then turn the dough out onto the floured surface.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Knead for a few minutes, adding flour as needed to keep the dough from feeling sticky.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Divide the dough into 3 equal sections. Roll each section into a long thin rope, then braid the ropes together&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the loaf on a cookie sheet covered with wax paper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prepare your egg wash by beating the egg yolks and water till smooth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a pastry brush to brush a thin layer of the mixture onto the visible surface of your challah.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat the oven to 350°F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let the loaf rise 30 to 45 minutes longer. You’ll know the dough is ready to bake when you press your finger into the dough and the indentation stays, rather than bouncing back.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake challah for 40 minutes, turning halfway through.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take the challah out of the oven. You can test the bread for doneness by turning it over and tapping on the bottom of the loaf—if it makes a hollow sound, it’s done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let challah cool on the baking sheet or a wire cooling rack before serving.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/pumpkin-challah.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/pumpkin-challah.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>bread</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Carrot Curry Soup</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon oil or unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ onion chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon red curry paste, or to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 pound carrots, peeled and chopped - ½-inch chunks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ 14-ounce can full-fat coconut milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon sea salt, or to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cups / 180 ml of water, or to cover&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 lemon (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large soup pan over medium-high heat add the butter and onion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stir until the onions are well-coated, and allow to saute until translucent, a few minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the curry paste, and then stir in the carrots.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow to cook another minute or two, and then add the coconut milk, salt, and water, adding more water to cover if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simmer until the carrots are tender, 10 - 15 minutes, then puree using a blender or hand blender until the soup is completely silky smooth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next part is important, you’re going to make any needed adjustments. For
example, add more water if the consistency needs to be thinned out a bit. Taste
for salt, adding more if needed. I also like to season this soup with a great
big squeeze or lemon or lime juice. Serve topped with whatever you have on
hand. Something crunchy like almonds is nice. Along with a final touch of
something green, like micro greens &amp;amp; cilantro.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/carrot-soup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/carrot-soup.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>soups</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pumpkin Spiced Pancakes</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1½ cups/192 grams all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ½ teaspoons baking powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ teaspoon baking soda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ teaspoon kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1½ teaspoons ground cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon ground ginger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅛ teaspoon freshly grated nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1½ cups buttermilk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup pumpkin purée&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons melted butter, plus more for greasing the skillet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large bowl, whisk the flour, sugar, baking powder, baking soda, salt and spices together until well combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a medium bowl, whisk the buttermilk, pumpkin purée, eggs, melted butter and vanilla extract until well combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the wet ingredients to the dry ingredients and gently fold with a rubber spatula until just combined. (A few small lumps are O.K.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat a lightly greased griddle or nonstick skillet over medium-low heat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drop the pancakes into the pan by the ¼ cup, making sure to leave plenty of room in between for the batter to expand.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook for a minute or two, until the batter bubbles at the edges and browns on the bottom, then carefully flip.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook another minute or two, until the batter is completely cooked through and the pancakes are puffy and deep golden brown.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Repeat until all of the batter is used. Serve the pancakes as you make them or keep the pancakes warm as you cook them by setting them on a baking sheet in a 250-degree oven.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/pumpkin-spiced-pancakes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/pumpkin-spiced-pancakes.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>breakfast</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
