<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 19:44:20 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 19:44:20 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creamy Smoked Gouda Brussels Sprouts</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ½ pounds brussels sprouts, stems trimmed and most of the sprouts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sliced in half&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ teaspoon ground mustard powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon cayenne pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cups whole milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sea salt and fresh cracked black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup diced yellow onion (from one small onion)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8 cloves of garlic, smashed and peeled but left whole&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup coarsely grated smoked Gouda cheese&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup coarsely grated aged Gouda cheese&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup panko bread crumbs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons fresh parsley&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sea salt and fresh cracked black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place a rack in the center of the oven and preheat oven to 375°F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring a large pot of salted water to a boil. When boiling, add the
brussels sprouts and simmer for 7 minutes, until they just begin to
tenderize. Drain into a colander, cover with ice and rinse with cool
water to stop the cooking process. Allow to rest while you assemble
the rest of the ingredients.
In a medium saucepan, melt butter over medium heat. Whisk in the
flour, and whisk until the mixture is combined and starts to bubble
slightly. Don’t let the mixture brown too much, but it’s ok if it
browns a bit.
Whisk in the spices and then slowly stream the milk into the butter
and flour mixture, whisking as you stir. Whisk nearly constantly and
as the milk comes to a light simmer it will begin to thicken slightly.
Add a good pinch of both salt and pepper.
Lower heat to low.
In a small skillet heat olive oil over medium heat. Add onions and
whole garlic cloves and saute until the onions are transluscent and
beginning to brown and the cloves are browned.
In a small bowl toss together smoked gouda cheese and cornstarch. Add
the cheese to the thickening milk mixture and stir to combine. The
cheese will begin to melt and the cornstarch will further thicken the
sauce as it begins to simmer.
Stir in the cooked onions and garlic.
Cook until mixture is silky smooth and thickened.
Melt remaining 1 tablespoon of butter in the medium skillet. Add the
breadcrumbs and parsley and toss until coated in butter and browned
slightly, about 4 minutes. Add a good pinch of salt and fresh cracked
black pepper and place in a small bowl until it’s time to layer
everything.
Transfer drained brussels sprouts to a 2-quart baking disk. Add the
aged gouda and toss to combine.
Pour the smoked Gruyere cheese sauce over the vegetable mixture.
Bake, uncovered, until bubbling and golden brown and the brussels
sprouts are completely tender, about 30 minutes. Remove from the oven
and top generously with breadcrumbs
Brussels sprouts can be made ahead of time by blanching the
vegetables, making the cheese sauce, assembling it all (except for the
bread crumbs!) in the baking dish, covered and refrigerated. Before
ready to serve, remove the cover from the dish, add the sauted bread
crumbs and bake as usual. Enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/gouda-brussel-sprouts.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/gouda-brussel-sprouts.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Turmeric Ginger Latte</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 heaped teaspoon peeled and finely chopped fresh turmeric&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon peeled and roughly chopped ginger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon sugar of choice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons coconut oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pinch sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup milk of choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine turmeric, ginger, sugar, coconut oil and a pinch of
sea salt in a powerful blender.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat milk in a small saucepan over medium heat until just
simmering.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour the hot milk into the blender and blitz everything
until smooth and frothy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/turmeric-latte.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/turmeric-latte.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dad&#39;s Sweet Potato Pie</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;for-the-crust&quot;&gt;For the Crust:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup (4 ounces) cold unsalted butter, cut into small cubes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1½ cup all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons granulated sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅓ cup cold buttermilk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;for-the-filling&quot;&gt;For the Filling:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cups mashed cooked sweet potatoes, from 2 medium sweet potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup packed brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ¼ teaspoon ground coriander&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon freshly grated nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ teaspoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup (2 ounces) unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ¼ cup (10 ounces) evaporated milk, divided&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅓ cup granulated sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 large eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon pure vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;to-make-the-pie-crust&quot;&gt;To make the pie crust&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a medium bowl whisk together flour, sugar, and salt. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add cold, cubed butter and, using your fingers (or a potato
masher), work the butter into the flour mixture. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quickly break the butter down into the flour mixture, some butter
pieces will be the size of oat flakes, some will be the size of peas. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a well in the mixture and pour in the cold buttermilk. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a fork to bring to dough together. Try to moisten all of the
flour bits. Add a bit more buttermilk if necessary, but you want to
mixture to be shaggy and not outwardly wet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On a lightly floured work surface, dump out the dough mixture. It
will be moist and shaggy. That’s perfect. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gently knead into a disk.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wrap the disk in plastic wrap and refrigerate for 1 hour. Allowing
the dough to rest in the refrigerator will help rechill the butter and
distribute the moisture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To roll out the pie crust, on a well floured surface, roll the
crust 1/8 inch thick and about 12 inches in diameter. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer it to a pie pan. Trim the edge almost even with the edge
of the pan Fold the edges under and crimp with your fingers or a fork.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover it with plastic wrap and refrigerate it for a minimum of 30
minutes and a maximum of 3 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;to-make-the-filling&quot;&gt;To make the filling&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat the oven to 375° F. Place a rack in the upper third of
the oven.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First peel the sweet potatoes. Dice the sweet
potatoes into large, 3-inch chunks. Place potato pieces in a large
pot and cover with cool water. Place over medium high heat and bring
to a boil. Reduce heat to medium and simmer until the potatoes are
tender throughout, about 20 minutes. Test the doneness of the
potatoes using a thin knife. If the knife meets any resistance,
simmer the potatoes a bit longer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drain into a colander.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same large pot place cooked potato pieces, the packed brown
sugar, all of the spices, salt, butter, and half of the evaporated
milk. Cook on low flame, using a potato masher to mash the potatoes
and they cook. Simmer for about 5 minutes. Make sure that the
mixture is as smooth as possible. I used an immersion blender to
completely smooth the mixture. Once mixture is smooth and fragrant,
remove from fire and let cool in pot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a medium bowl, whisk together the remaining evaporated milk,
granulated sugar, eggs, and vanilla extract. Whisk well. Pour the
egg mixture into the warm sweet potato mixture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pour the prepared filling into the pie crust. Place on a baking sheet
and bake for 10 minutes at 375° F. Reduce the heat to 325
degrees F and cook until cooked through, about 45 to 50 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To test the pie for doneness lightly shake the baking sheet. If the
center of the pie has a wavy jiggle it needs more time in the oven.
If the center of the pie has a lighter, more structured jiggle, it’s
done! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/sweet-potato-pie.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sweet-potato-pie.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lemon Ricotta Pancakes</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup ricotta&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 large eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zest of one lemon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ½ cups coconut flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp coconut flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ½ tsp baking powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Butter or oil for the pan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a blender, combine ricotta, eggs, lemon juice, water and lemon zest.
Blend until well mixed, about 10 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add flour, sweetener, coconut flour, baking powder and salt and blend
until mixture is smooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heat a griddle or large skillet over medium heat and add butter or
oil. Once pan is hot, spoon about 3 tbsp of batter into 4 inch circles
and let cook until edges look dry, a few small bubbles appear on the
top, and the underside is golden brown. Flip carefully and continue to
cook until second side is golden brown, about 2 to 3 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove and keep pancakes warm while repeating with remaining batter.
You should get about 12 pancakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve pancakes with butter and mixed berry syrup.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/lemon-ricotta-pancakes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/lemon-ricotta-pancakes.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dark Chocolate Guinness Brownies</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup Guinness stout&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10 ounces bittersweet chocolate, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 ounces unsweetened chocolate, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup (2 sticks) unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1½ cups granulated sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 large eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoons kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ teaspoon baking soda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place a rack in the center of the oven and preheat oven to 350° F.
Lightly grease a pan with non-stick cooking and line an 8x8-inch
baking sheet with parchment paper, so that the paper hangs over the
edge of the pan a bit. Lightly grease the parchment paper and set the
pan aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a small saucepan over medium heat, bring the beer to a simmer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simmer until the beer is reduced to about ⅓ cup. This will take
about 10 to 12 minutes. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove from heat and allow to cool slightly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place chocolate and butter in a medium heatproof bowl. Bring a
medium pot with a few inches of water to a simmer. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the chocolate and butter mixture over the simmering water to
melt both. Stir as they melt together.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove the bowl from the simmering water and allow to cool
slightly, we’re talking 5 to 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whisk in the sugar until combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whisk in the eggs, one at a time, until the chocolate mixture is
smooth and almost glossy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whisk in the vanilla extract and the beer reduction.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the flour, salt, and baking soda and stir to combine, making
sure there are no hidden flour pockets.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour into the prepared pan and bake for 35-40 minutes until a
toothpick inserted in the brownies comes our with only a few moist
crumbs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow to cool for at least 30 minutes before removing from the pan
and slicing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/guinness-brownies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/guinness-brownies.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creamy (Gluten-Free) Pasta with Chicken and Broccoli</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ box gluten-free pasta (I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.simpletruth.com/products/grains-pastas-sauces/pasta/gluten-free-fusilli/&quot;&gt;Simple Truth Gluten Free Fusili&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 can full-fat coconut cream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tbsp olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 head broccoli&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ lb chicken breast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup grated parmesan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt, pepper, and minced garlic to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chop broccoli and chicken into 1-inch cubes. Smaller is better!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Divide olive oil between two sauce pans.  Heat each about 2 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add broccoli to one pan, in even layer, stirring to coat with olive oil.  Add salt, pepper, and minced garlic to taste (I do 1 tsp each).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add chicken to other pan, similarly coating and seasoning. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stir broccoli and chicken occassionally. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring a pot of ~4 quarts of water to boil (is your stovetop looking crowded yet?).  Add 1 tbsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour in pasta, and boil for 8-10 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once broccoli and chicken are starting to turn golden-brown, remove from heat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drain pasta, and add broccoli and chicken to the pot.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/broccoli-gf-pasta.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/broccoli-gf-pasta.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>mains</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>No Knead Bread</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 cups all purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1½ teaspoons salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon instant yeast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1½ cups room temperature water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;dough-prep&quot;&gt;Dough Prep:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whisk the flour, salt, and yeast together until mixed. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stir in the water until a chunky, thick dough forms. It’s gonna look scrappy and weird and you’re going to question whether or not this will work, but it will. (Just a reminder: do not knead. NO KNEAD BREAD.) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover with plastic wrap and let it rest for 12-18 hours. Overnight is ideal here, kids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;prep-for-baking&quot;&gt;PREP FOR BAKING:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you’re ready to bake, preheat the oven to 450. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stick a 6 quart enamel coated cast iron Lodge Dutch Oven (or similar) in the oven for about 30 minutes to heat. At this point, the dough should be big and puffy and pretty loose, with little bubbles in it. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gently scrape the dough out onto a well-floured surface. (Remember: NO KNEAD.) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gently shape it into a ball with flour on the outside and cover with plastic while your pan heats up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;bake&quot;&gt;Bake:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When the pan is hot, line it with parchment paper (BE CAREFUL! I use a wooden spoon to just sort of press it in there) and carefully transfer your dough ball into the pan. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake, covered, for 30 minutes. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove the cover and bake another 10-15 minutes to get the exterior nice and golden brown and crispy. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voila! Done. Miracle no-knead bread, you boss you.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/no-knead-bread.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/no-knead-bread.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Corn Tortilla Soup</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 sweet onion, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 cloves garlic, minced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons ground cumin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon smoked paprika&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 cups chicken stock&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 (4-inch) corn tortillas, cut into pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅓ cup fresh cilantro, plus extra for topping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 pound shredded chicken breast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 ears fresh corn, kernels cut from the cob&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tortilla chips for serving&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sliced avocado for serving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h4&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/corn-tortilla-soup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/corn-tortilla-soup.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Baked Churros</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons light brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon table salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅓ cup margarine or unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 large eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon ground cinnamon (or to taste)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 425°F.  Cover two baking sheets with parchment paper; set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a medium saucepan, stir together 1 cup water, brown sugar and salt. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add butter and place over medium-high heat.  Heat until butter is melted and mixture starts to boil. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove from heat and add flour, stirring with a wooden spoon. Mixture will clump and pull away from the sides of the pan.  Mix/mash with wooden spoon until no streaks of flour can be seen.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a small bowl, combine eggs and vanilla. Scramble mixture with a fork and then add to the dough-ball in the saucepan.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stir and mash, breaking up the dough until loosened. Stir well until eggs are incorporated and mixture has the appearance of mashed potatoes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer dough to a piping bag fitted with decorator tip.  You could also pipe the dough in a zip-top bag with the corner snipped, but the churros will be ridge-less (delicious, nonetheless).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pipe dough into long thin lengths on the parchment covered pans. Use a pair of kitchen scissors to cut the end of the dough from the piping tip. Leave about 2-inches of space between the churros.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 10-12 minutes or until slightly puffed.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn oven to broiler setting and watch carefully as churros toast and turn deep golden brown.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove from oven and let cool slightly. Transfer to a wire cooling rack. If you’re baking the churros one pan at a time, be sure to return the oven setting to 425°F before putting in the next pan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine sugar and cinnamon and pour onto a long dish. Roll churros in mixture.  Serve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/churros.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/churros.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>snacks</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pumpkin Curry</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 carrots, sliced
1 medium yellow onion, diced
1 medium head of broccoli, also diced
1 14 oz can coconut cream (or milk)
1 regular sized can pumpkin puree
1 cup chicken stock
2 tablespoons oil of choice (I use olive)
1 teaspoon ground ginger 
1 teaspoon crushed garlic
1 teaspoon coriander
½ tablespoon turmeric powder
1 tablespoon curry powder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a wok, saute the onion, carrots, and broccoli in the oil over medium 
heat until the onions become translucent&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn up the heat on the veggies to medium high (7-8), add the can of coconut
cream to the wok.  Let it sizzle and stir until the cream is melted and mixed well with the veggies.  Turn down to medium low and let it simmer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While the concoction is simmering, add the pumpkin, chicken stock, and spices
. Stir to combine.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the peeled and de-veined shrimp to the soup and cook until the shrimp are pink and firm (about 3-4 more minutes).  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Goes great with brown rice!  Garnish with cashews, cilantro, or coconut flakes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/pumpkin-curry.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/pumpkin-curry.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>mains</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
