<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 08:26:15 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 08:26:15 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Carrot Ginger Coconut Soup</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 medium onion, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons minced ginger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/4 teaspoon ground coriander&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4-5 cups diced carrots&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 cups vegetable broth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup light coconut milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;salt and pepper to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat olive oil in a large saucepan over medium heat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add onions and saute until onions are translucent, about 4 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add ginger and saute for another 4 minutes, until softened and fragrant.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add coriander and diced carrots.  Stir to incorporate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the vegetable broth, reduce heat, and simmer mixture until carrots are completely softened, about 30 minutes.  Remove from heat and allow to cool for 20 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using a blender, blend soup in batches until smooth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Return soup to pot, stir in coconut milk.  Add salt and pepper to taste.  Serve soup warm with crusty vegan bread.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/carrot-ginger-soup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/carrot-ginger-soup.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kale Apple Soup</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large bunch kale (about 10 ounces)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup cubed pancetta or sliced bacon (about 2 ounces)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 cups warmed chicken or vegetable stock, divided&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 whole yellow onion, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 teaspoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 medium apple, cored and chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup crème fraîche, mascarpone cheese, or plain yogurt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Freshly ground black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wash the kale and remove the bottom inch of stem. Chop roughly into 1-inch pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a large skillet over medium heat, sauté the pancetta for 1 minute or until just barely showing color. Add the kale and stir to coat with rendered fat. (Add a glug of olive oil if pancetta didn’t render enough fat to keep the kale from sticking to the pan.) Cook, stirring, until the kale begins to wilt, about 5 minutes. Add 2 cups chicken stock, lower heat to medium-low and cook, stirring occasionally, for about 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transfer the mixture to a blender; or blend with an immersion blender. (Fill the blender no more than halfway; puree in two batches if necessary.) Puree, starting on the lowest speed, until smooth. (When working with hot liquids in a blender, it’s wise to hold down the lid with a kitchen towel in case some liquid escapes when the motor is running.) Puree the second batch if necessary. Pour into a large bowl and set aside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same skillet over medium heat, heat the olive oil and cook the onions with the salt until the onions just barely show color, stirring for about 3 minutes. Add the chopped apples and cook, stirring occasionally, for 5 minutes, or until the apples soften and onions are translucent. Stir in the remaining broth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transfer the mixture to the blender, splitting into two batches if necessary. Puree until smooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combine the pureed apple and onion mixture with the kale mixture, and whisk to combine. If soup seems too thick, add more stock or water until it reaches the desired consistency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reheat if necessary, and serve garnished with a dollop of crème fraîche, mascarpone cheese, or plain yogurt and a few grinds of black pepper.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/kale-apple-soup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kale-apple-soup.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Best Hot Cereal</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/4 cup water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup Bob’s Red Mill 7 Grain Hot Cereal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 teaspoon orange rind, finely grated&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 dash kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 dash ground cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 pinch fresh ground nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4-5 tablespoons vanilla soy milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 drops vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons maple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a small pot, add orange rind to water and bring to a boil.
Add cereal, salt, cinnamon, and nutmeg and reduce heat. Stir while cooking and add the soy milk a tablespoon at a time when liquid has been fully absorbed by the cereal.
When the cereal is done, about 6 minutes, add vanilla extract, butter, and maple syrup. Stir to mix and serve hot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/hot-cereal.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/hot-cereal.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Herb-crusted Pork Loin</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;for-the-pork&quot;&gt;For the Pork&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2lb pork tenderloin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup of finely chopped herbs (I chose thyme, sage, and rosemary)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup parsley&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10 cloves garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon lemon zest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 teaspoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;for-the-sauce&quot;&gt;For the Sauce&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 lemons, zested and juiced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 garlic cloves, minced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/3 cup white wine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;for-the-veggies&quot;&gt;For the Veggies&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1.5 lbs asparagus (this was about 3 bunches), tough ends cut off&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 lbs small new potatoes, halved&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;drizzle of olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;salt &amp;amp; pepper to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 lemon, juiced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat oven to 425°F
Make the herb paste - Place herbs, parsley, garlic (yes, all 10!), salt, pepper and lemon zest in a food processor and pulse until it becomes very coarse. Add oil and scrape down the sides if necessary, pulse until just combined. 
Rub paste on your pork. I chose to just cover the top and sides, leaving the bottom of the pork clean. Place pork on a pan.
Prep your potatoes - Place halved new potatoes in a bowl and toss with a drizzle of olive oil until coated.
Place potatoes on a baking sheet and sprinkle with salt &amp;amp; pepper. Line asparagus on a smaller baking sheet, brush with olive oil and sprinkle with salt &amp;amp; pepper.
Place pork, potatoes, &amp;amp; asparagus in oven at the same time (I moved two racks as close to the center as possible, placed pork on the bottom and veggies on the top). Roast the pork for 30-40 minutes or until the internal temperature reaches 140°F. Cover pork with foil and let sit for about 15 minutes before cutting. Cook potatoes until they are easily pierced with a fork (30-35 minutes). When potatoes are done, toss them in lemon juice. 
While everything is cooking, make the white wine sauce. Heat olive oil in a medium sized skillet over medium heat. Add garlic and cook, stirring, until fragrant. Add lemon juice and white wine and increase the heat to medium-high. Simmer until liquid has reduced by half (about 5 minutes). Season with a pinch of salt and pepper. Add 2 tablespoons of water along with the butter and turn off the heat once it is melted. Stir to combine.
Cut your pork loin into 1/2 inch slices. To assemble your plates, place about 4 slices of porkloin and generous portions of potatoes and asparagus on each plate. Top the pork with a spoonful of the garlic, wine sauce and ENJOY!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/herb-crusted-pork-loin.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/herb-crusted-pork-loin.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Broccoli Cheddar Soup</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup cheddar cheese&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup milk of choice (unsweetened!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1½ cup fresh or frozen cauliflower or broccoli&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup chicken stock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Steam the broccoli or cauliflower until soft. I typically put the veg in a container with about a tablespoon of water in the microwave for 5 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add all ingredients to blender&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blend until smooth, about 3-4 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: This only makes about 1 serving! Double or quadruple for more people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/broccoli-cheddar-soup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/broccoli-cheddar-soup.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>soups</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Super-Seeded Pumpkin Cake Bread</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup (1 stick) unsalted butter, at room temperature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cups all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon baking soda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon baking powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;11/2 teaspoons pumpkin pie spice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 teaspoon nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 teaspoon cardamom&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 teaspoon black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup packed brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 large eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup canned pumpkin puree&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/3 cup buttermilk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;for-the-topping&quot;&gt;For the topping&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup coarsely chopped walnuts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup coarsely chopped pecans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup pumpkin seeds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons sunflower seeds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon millet (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Any other bits of nuts and seeds you’d like!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place a rack in the center of the oven and preheat to 350°F. Grease a 9x5 loaf pan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a medium bowl whisk together the flour, baking soda, baking powder, pumpkin pie spice, cinnamon, nutmeg, cardamom, salt, and pepper. Set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the bowl of a stand mixer fitted with a paddle attachment, beat the butter and brown sugar for 3-5 minutes until slightly pale and fluffy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beat in the eggs one at a time, beating for 1 minute between each addition.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the pumpkin puree and beat until combined&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the buttermilk and vanilla and beat well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stop the mixer and remove the bowl. Add in the flour mixture all at once, and stir gently with a spatula until just combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spoon the batter into the prepared pan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sprinkle with the nuts and seeds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 45-55 minutes, until a toothpick inserted comes out clean. Let cool for 15 minutes on a wire rack before serving warm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/super-seeded-pumpkin-cake-bread.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/super-seeded-pumpkin-cake-bread.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>desserts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cauliflower Blueberry Smoothie</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp almond butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ½ cups frozen cauliflower&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 scoop protein powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup frozen blueberries&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup milk of choice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ frozen avocado&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ tsp organic cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blend! Pour!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/cauliflower-smoothie.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/cauliflower-smoothie.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chicken Zoodles</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 medium chicken breasts, cut into ½” pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 cloves garlic, minced or crushed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 zucchini, spiralized&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon red pepper flakes (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;salt &amp;amp; pepper, to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat a large heavy-duty pan to medium/high heat. Add olive oil and minced garlic. Cook garlic for 30 seconds to 1 minute or until fragrant. Be careful not to burn the garlic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add chicken, red pepper flakes and salt &amp;amp; pepper. Cook chicken for 5-6 minutes or until golden and cooked through.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Toss in spiralized zoodles and cook for 1 minute then turn off heat. Sprinkle with parmesan cheese if desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/chicken-zoodles.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/chicken-zoodles.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roasted Fall Vegetable Soup</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 medium leeks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 medium parsnips, peeled and cut crosswise into ½-inch pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 medium carrots, peeled and cut crosswise into ½-inch pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 (2-pound) butternut squash, or any type of winter squash, peeled and cut into ½-inch cubes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 large or 3 medium celery stalks, cut crosswise into ½-inch pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 medium celery root, peeled and cut into ½-inch cubes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 shallots, peeled and quartered&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8 garlic cloves, thinly sliced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ½ tablespoons chopped fresh thyme leaves, or 2 teaspoons dried&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Freshly ground black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 cups vegetable stock or canned low-sodium broth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup dry white wine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Position a rack in the middle of the oven and preheat to 400°F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trim off the dark green sections from the leeks and save for making vegetable stock. Halve the pale green and white sections lengthwise. Rinse under cold running water, pat dry, and cut crosswise into ½-inch pieces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In one large or two medium very shallow roasting pan(s) or rimmed baking sheet(s), combine the leeks, parsnips, carrots, squash, celery, celery root, shallots, garlic, and thyme.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drizzle with the olive oil, season with salt and pepper, and toss to evenly coat the vegetables. You don’t want to have vegetables on top of one another; you want them in a single layer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roast the vegetables for 20 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn the oven temperature to 450°F and roast for another 10 minutes, or until the vegetables are a nice golden-brown, almost crispy on the edges, and almost soft when you gently test them with a fork or small, sharp knife. You don’t want them soft and mushy; they will continue cooking in the soup.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, in a large stockpot over high heat, bring the vegetable stock to a boil. Turn the heat to medium-low and gently simmer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove the vegetables from the oven, add the wine, and deglaze the pan, using a spatula to loosen any bits clinging to the bottom. Pour every­thing from the baking sheet into the stock. Turn the heat to low and simmer, partially covered, for 20 to 30 minutes. Taste and adjust the seasoning, adding more salt and pepper if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/roasted-fall-vegetable-soup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/roasted-fall-vegetable-soup.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gluten-Free Apple Crisp</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;apples&quot;&gt;Apples&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 cups of peeled, sliced apples&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tsp cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;topping&quot;&gt;Topping&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup ground almonds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅔ cup brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅔ cup rice flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup melted butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 350°F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix apples, sugar and cinnamon in a microwave safe bowl. Cook apple mixture in the microwave for 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, mix topping together in a bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dump apple mixture into an 8x8 square baking dish. Crumble topping over top.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 30 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/apple-crisp.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/apple-crisp.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
