<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 05:11:56 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 05:11:56 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Strawberry Rhubarb Pie</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;for-the-crust&quot;&gt;For the Crust&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 ½ cup all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ teaspoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup (2 sticks) unsalted butter, cold, cut into cubes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup cold buttermilk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;for-the-filling&quot;&gt;For the Filling&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 cups ½-inch thick sliced rhubarb (about 1 pound)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 pound strawberries, hulled and sliced in half&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅓ cup light brown sugar, packed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup granulated sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;large pinch of salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons fresh lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;to-make-the-crust&quot;&gt;To make the crust&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a medium bowl, whisk together flour, sugar and salt. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add cold, cubed butter and, using your fingers, work the butter into the flour mixture. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quickly break the butter down into the flour mixture. Some butter pieces will be the size of oat flakes; some will be the size of peas. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a well in the mixture and pour in the cold buttermilk. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a fork to bring the dough together. Try to moisten all of the flour bits. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On a lightly floured work surface, dump out the dough mixture. It will be moist and shaggy. That’s perfect. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Divide the dough in two and gently knead into two disks. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wrap each disk in plastic wrap and refrigerate for 1 hour. Allowing the dough to rest in the refrigerator will help rechill the butter and distribute the moisture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;to-make-the-filling&quot;&gt;To make the filling&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a medium bowl, toss together rhubarb, strawberries, sugars, cornstarch, salt, and lemon juice.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Toss until all of the fruit is covered in a coating of sugar and cornstarch.  The cornstarch will disappear and the sugars will begin to make juice with the fruit.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow to rest at room temperature while you make the topping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;to-assemble&quot;&gt;To assemble&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To assemble the pie, on a well-floured surface, roll the bottom crust 1/8″ thick and about 12″ in diameter. Transfer it to a pie pan. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trim the edge almost even with the edge of the pan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spoon filling into piecrust.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roll out the top crust in the same manner. Use a pizza slicer to slice the dough into 1-inch wide strips and weave the crust strips on top of the pie. Use this guide to help you:
http://www.thekitchn.com/how-to-make-a-lattice-pie-crust-cooking-lessons-from-the-kitchn-191672&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To finish, place a rack in the center of the oven and preheat oven to 400° F. Line a baking sheet with parchment paper and set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brush the egg wash over pie crust, then sprinkle with sugar.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place pie on baking sheet and bake for 15 minutes, then reduce the temperature to 350°F and bake the pie for 30 minutes more, or until the crust is golden and the filling is bubbling. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove from the oven and allow to cool completely before serving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/strawberry-rhubarb-pie.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/strawberry-rhubarb-pie.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>desserts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Crispy Blackened Tofu Tacos</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 package extra firm tofu (approx. 14-16 ounces)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons smoked paprika&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon dried thyme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon ground cumin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼-½ teaspoon cayenne&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons arrowroot powder (or cornstarch)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10 tortillas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;cabbage-slaw&quot;&gt;Cabbage Slaw&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ head red cabbage, thinly sliced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ head green cabbage, thinly sliced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup apple cider vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;avocado-lime-crema&quot;&gt;Avocado-Lime Crema&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 avocados&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup cilantro leaves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 garlic cloves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;juice of 3 limes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;diced green onions for topping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Drain and rinse tofu and then press it by placing between two kitchen towels and topping with a heavy book. Allow to sit for at least 30 minutes so that excess moisture is drawn out. Alternatively, you can accomplish this by using a tofu press.
Next preheat the oven to 400°F and then line a baking sheet with parchment paper. Begin preparing the slaw by combining the cabbage with the vinegar and salt in a large bowl. Massage it with your hands for a few minutes then set it aside to marinate.
Once the tofu has been pressed, dice it into 1-inch cubes and then transfer to the baking sheet. Bake in the oven for 10 minutes on each side until it’s light golden brown. Then turn the oven off and set tofu aside to cool.
Meanwhile mix together the spices (paprika to pepper) in a large bowl. Using your hands, lightly coat the tofu with one tablespoon of oil and then transfer it to the bowl with the spices. Coat each piece evenly then sprinkle the starch on top. Mix with your hands or a spoon until each piece is coated with the starch as well.
Warm the remaining 2 tablespoons of oil in a skillet over medium heat and then saute the tofu on for about 5 minutes on each side. Depending on the size of your skillet, you might have to do this part in two steps, using one tablespoon of oil at a time.
Allow the tofu to sit in the skillet on warm then prepare the avocado crema by placing all of the ingredients in a food processor and blending until smooth.
Warm the tortillas (I usually microwave them for 15-20 seconds) then place tofu inside. Top with cabbage and avocado cream and serve immediately.
Tofu and cabbage can be made ahead of time and stored in an airtight container in the fridge for up to 4 days. The avocado crema can be stored for up to 2 days.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/crispy-tofu-tacos.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/crispy-tofu-tacos.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Protein Pancakes</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup rolled oats (11 g protein)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 tablespoons (60g) hemp hearts (18 grams protein)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon baking powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon cinnamon, plus more for sprinkling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ teaspoon sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 large eggs (8 g protein) or 4 large egg whites&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup plain, unsweetened Greek yogurt (12-14 g protein)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅓ cup almond milk or water, plus more if needed for thinning batter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon sugar, optional&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat an electric or stovetop griddle.
While griddle is preheating, place all of the pancake ingredients
into a blender jar in the order listed. Pulse a few times, then blend
until smooth. Add a little more almond milk or water, if needed. The
batter should be pourable, but not too thick or too thin.
Lightly grease the preheated griddle with butter or oil, if
needed. (I use one that doesn’t require greasing first.) Using about 2
tablespoons of better per pancake, pour batter onto the hot griddle.
Let cook for 1-2 minutes on the first side, then flip and cook for
another few minutes until cooked through. Transfer to a plate and keep
warm until ready to serve.
Repeat process with remaining batter, being sure to grease griddle
well between each batch to prevent sticking.
To serve, divide the pancakes between two plates. Spread each
pancake with a little almond butter and top with fruit. Sprinkle with
cinnamon and a few more hemp hearts, if desired. Serve warm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/protein-pancakes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/protein-pancakes.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Strawberry Raspberry Fudge</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup fresh strawberries, roughly chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup fresh raspberries&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons maple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup coconut cream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup cashews, soaked for an hour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons coconut oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add strawberries and raspberries to a blender and puree until smooth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then add maple syrup, vanilla, coconut cream, soaked cashews, and coconut oil and blend at the highest power for 10-15 seconds until smooth and creamy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now you can do two things. Either pour the mixture into silicone cups OR pour the mixture onto parchment paper, smooth out and garnish
with shredded coconut and chocolate chips. Make these treats however you’d like to eat them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place in freeze to freeze for 2+ hours. Serve immediately and store in freezer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/strawberry-truffles.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/strawberry-truffles.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Flourless Chocolate Cake</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 tbsp unsalted butter, plus more for greasing the pan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8 ounces of semisweet chocolate, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 large eggs, separated&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup granulated sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;confectioners’ sugar, for dusting optional&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 275°. Line the bottom of a springform pan with parchment paper and butter the sides and parchment paper. It is important to grease the pan (sides and bottom) very well so that the cake doesn’t stick.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a double boiler, melt butter and chocolate together, once melted, remove from heat and cool.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, with an electric mixer beat egg whites until soft peaks form. Once soft peaks have formed, gradually add in the sugar and beat until you see glossy, stiff peaks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once chocolate is cooled, (it is very important that it is cooled as to not cook the eggs.) whisk in the egg yolks. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer chocolate mixture to a large bowl and whisk in ¼ of the egg whites into the chocolate before folding in the remaining egg whites. Be sure to fold them in well as to not have pockets of egg whites because this will cause the cake to react funnily while baking.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour batter into the greased pan, smooth the top with a spatula and bake for 45-50 minutes. Cool completely before removing sides of the pan, and serve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/flourless-chocolate-cake.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/flourless-chocolate-cake.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chocolate Pie</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;13 ounces semisweet chocolate chips&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅓ cup coffee liqueur&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 pound silken tofu, drained&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon honey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 9-inch prepared chocolate wafer crust (store-bought is fine)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place enough water in the bottom of a 4-quart saucepan to come 1 inch up the sides. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring to a simmer over medium heat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Melt the chocolate chips with the liqueur and vanilla in a medium
metal bowl set over the simmering water, stirring often with a rubber
or silicone spatula. (Although vanilla extract is often added at the
very end of cooking, the melting chocolate will never get hot enough
to damage the delicate sensibilities.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine the tofu, honey and chocolate mixture in a blender or food
processor and spin until smooth ( about 1 minute).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour the filling into the crust and refrigerate for 2 hours, or
until the filling sets firm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/moo-less-chocolate-pie.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/moo-less-chocolate-pie.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chocolate Souffles</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup unsalted butter, at room temperature plus extra for the&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ramekins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cups granulated sugar, plus extra for the ramekins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 large eggs, at room temperature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅓ cup all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅓ cup cocoa powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon baking powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅓ cup milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon espresso powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat oven to 325° F. Coat four 6-ounce ramekins with butter
and sprinkle the insides with granulated sugar. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring a kettle of water to a boil while you prepare the batter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whisk together the flour, cocoa, baking powder and salt. Set aside
Puree the butter, sugar and eggs for 1 minute in a blender for 1
minute.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Warm the milk and vanilla extract by microwaving on high for 30
second. Add the instant espresso powder and stir until dissolved.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add half of the flour mixture to the butter to the blender and
puree for 30 seconds. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the milk mixture and puree again for 30 seconds. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the remaining flour and puree for 1 minute.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Divide batter evenly among prepared ramekins.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set the ramekins in an 8-inch square pan and set the pan on the
oven rack. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour hot water in bottom of pans to 1/8 inch deep and slide
into the oven. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 45-50 minutes or until toothpick inserted
comes out clean.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove pans from oven and let ramekins stand in water for 5
minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove ramekins from water and cool slightly before serving. The
soufflés can be served straight from the cups or inverted onto a
plate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/chocolate-souffles.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/chocolate-souffles.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pesto Pasta with Shrimp</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;pesto&quot;&gt;Pesto&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cups fresh basil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup shredded Romano or Parmesan-Reggiano cheese&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅓ cup nut of choice (we had success with walnuts)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 teaspoons minced garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;pasta&quot;&gt;Pasta&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup shrimp, fully cooked and cut into ¼ inch chunks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cups grape tomatoes, cut into quarters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 box pasta (we use gluten free)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a blender or food processor, combine all pesto ingredients&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move the pesto into a pot on low heat, adding the tomatoes and
shrimp to heat up.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour the pasta into a large pot, then fill with water until it’s
about an inch above the pasta. Add 1 teaspoon of salt and boil.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strain the pasta, stir in the pesto, and enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/pesto-shrimp-pasta.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/pesto-shrimp-pasta.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>mains</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spicy Hot Chocolate</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 cups Silk Unsweetened Almondmilk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 teaspoons ground cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 ounces 75% dark chocolate (the darker the better!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅓ cup cocoa powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large pinch cayenne pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅓ cup coconut sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 pinch sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coconut cream, whipped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large slow cooker, combine all ingredients except the coconut cream and stir.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover and cook on low for two hours, whisking every now and again to combine the ingredients.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once completely melted, ladle into mugs and top with a heaping spoonful of coconut cream. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sprinkle with extra cinnamon and shaved chocolate to garnish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/spicy-hot-chocolate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/spicy-hot-chocolate.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pumpkin Hot Chocolate</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cups milk of your choice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cups pumpkin puree&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons cocoa powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons maple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoons vanilla&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dash sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dash cinnamon, optional&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;stevia, to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blend all.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat everything to a low simmer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve when it reaches your desired temperature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can it get any easier?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/pumpkin-hot-chocolate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/pumpkin-hot-chocolate.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
