<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 15:16:41 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 15:16:41 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lavender Egg Bread</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 tablespoons butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup whole milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup honey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1½ tablespoons dried lavender&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon active dry yeast (1 packet + ½ teaspoon)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 large eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3½ to 4 cups all purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1½ teaspoons salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a small saucepan over low heat, melt the butter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the milk, honey, and lavender and stir until the honey is dissolved.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove the pan from the heat and let cool to just above room temperature, about 110°F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer the milk mixture to the bowl of a stand mixer fitted with the dough hook attachment and sprinkle the yeast over the mixture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add 2 of the eggs, 3½ cups of flour and the salt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beat on medium speed until it forms a soft and smooth dough, about 8 to 10 minutes. Add the remaining flour if you find the dough is too sticky.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lightly grease a large bowl. Place the dough in the bowl, cover and allow to rest in a warm place for 1½ to 2 hours, or until doubled in size.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer dough to a lightly greased work surface and divide dough into three equal pieces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gently roll and stretch each piece into a 15-inch rope. Cover with a kitchen towel and allow to rest for 10 minutes. Continue rolling each rope until it is about 18-inches long.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lay the three ropes parallel to one another and pinch the three ropes together at the top.  Lightly and gently life each rope to braid the loaf.  Repeat until the braid is complete and pinch the ends of the rope together.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Line a rimmed baking sheet with parchment paper and lightly grease.  Carefully lift the braid and place on the prepared pan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover the loaf with lightly greased plastic wrap and allow to rise again for 1 hour.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Towards the end of the rising time, place a rack in the center of the oven and preheat oven to 375°F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lightly brush loaf with beaten egg.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the loaf and baking sheet on another baking sheet to insulate the bottom of the loaf and keep it from browning too quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 20 minutes, remove from the oven and lightly cover with foil.  Return to the oven and bake for another 20 to 25 minutes until a deep golden brown and the loaf sounds a bit hallow when it tapped.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove from the oven and allow to cool completely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/lavender-egg-bread.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/lavender-egg-bread.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>bread</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pumpkin Pie with a Speculoos Cookie Crust and Crème Fraîche Swirl</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;for-the-speculoos-cookie-crust&quot;&gt;For the Speculoos Cookie Crust:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8 ounces speculoos cookies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon dark brown sugar, tightly packed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅓ cup Vermont Creamery Maple and Sea Salt Cultured Butter, melted and cooled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;for-the-pumpkin-custard-filling-and-crème-fraîche-swirl&quot;&gt;For the Pumpkin Custard Filling and Crème Fraîche Swirl:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 can (15 ounces) pumpkin puree&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅔ cup (4.70 ounces) granulated sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons dark brown sugar, tightly packed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons ground cardamom&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon ground cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon kosher sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 can (14 ounces) sweetened condensed milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 large eggs, at room temperature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 ounces Vermont Creamery Vanilla Bean Crème Fraîche&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;for-the-speculoos-cookie-crust-1&quot;&gt;For the Speculoos Cookie Crust:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Center a rack in the oven and preheat to 350°F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a food processor, combine speculoos cookies, 1 tablespoon dark brown sugar, and 1 teaspoon kosher salt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pulse together until coarse and well combined. While pulsing, stream in melted butter and continue pulsing until the crumbs come together in giant clumps.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a rubber spatula to transfer the crumbs into a 9-inch tart pan with high sides and a removable bottom — there’s no need to grease the pan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use your fingers and the back of your hands to press the crumbs onto the bottom and sides of the pan, creating an even layer. The bottom and sides of the crust should be around ¼-inch thick.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake in the preheated oven for 8 minutes, then transfer to a wire rack to cool slightly while you make the filling. Be sure to keep the oven on!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;for-the-pumpkin-custard-filling-and-crème-fraîche-swirl-1&quot;&gt;For the Pumpkin Custard Filling and Crème Fraîche Swirl:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large, heavy-bottomed pot over medium heat, combine 1 can pumpkin puree, ⅔ cup granulated sugar, 2 tablespoons dark brown sugar, 2 teaspoons ground cardamom, 1 teaspoon ground cinnamon, and ½ teaspoon kosher sea salt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook for 5 minutes, using a heatproof rubber spatula to scrape the bottom and sides of the pan frequently. The mixture should start to sputter around 2 to 3 minutes in, and by 5 minutes, become thick and glossy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove from heat and slowly stream in 1 can sweetened condensed milk while continuing to whisk the mixture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue whisking until the sweetened condensed milk is fully incorporated, before whisking in 2 large eggs, one at a time, only adding the second egg when the first one has fully incorporated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the eggs are fully incorporated, pour the mixture into the prepared cookie crust shell.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer 2 ounces crème fraîche into a piping bag (or, in a pinch, a Ziploc bag with the corner snipped off) and drizzle the crème fraîche over the mixture in the pattern you desire (you can use this awesome Food52 guide for a quick tutorial on marbling). Use a bamboo skewer or toothpick with a sharp point to swirl the crème fraîche across the filling.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 35 to 40 minutes in the preheated oven, or until the edges of the filling have set. The filling may have bubbled and puffed slightly in the oven, but don’t worry — it settles down as it cools. You can use a knife to tap on the sides of the tart pan to test the filling; the middle should wobble slightly, but the edges should stay in the same place. Be careful not to overcook — it’s better to pull it out of the oven earlier than later, as the filling will continue to cook after it’s pulled out the oven.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer to a wire rack and cool completely until fully set.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve at room temperature, or chilled for an hour. This pie is best the day it’s made (since the crust will remain crunchy, but will soften the longer it sits).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/speculoos-pumpkin-pie.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/speculoos-pumpkin-pie.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Soft Gingerbread Cookies</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 ½ cups all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon baking soda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon ground cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ½ teaspoon ground ginger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ teaspoon ground cloves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ teaspoon kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ teaspoon ground nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon ground all-spice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup unsalted butter (2 sticks), room temperature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup light or dark brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large egg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 tablespoons unsulfured molasses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅓ cup diced crystallized ginger (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons turbinado sugar (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a medium bowl, sift together the all-purpose flour, baking soda, cinnamon, ginger, cloves, salt, nutmeg and all-spice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To a large bowl, add the room temperature butter and brown sugar.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using a stand-up mixer with the paddle attachment, cream the two together until the butter is light and fluffy, about 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the egg and molasses and beat until combined, an additional minute.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In two batches, add the dry ingredients to the wet ingredients, combining in between batches.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you see no traces of flour, fold in the crystallized ginger, making sure it’s evenly distributed throughout the dough (you might need to use your fingers because the ginger might stick together).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover the bowl with plastic wrap and transfer to the refrigerator to chill for 1 hour.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat your oven to 350 degrees F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour the turbinado sugar into a shallow plate. Using a 2-ounce ice cream scoop or 2 teaspoons, scoop out a ball of dough and roll it between your palms until it’s an even 1½-inch circle.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roll the ball of dough in the turbinado, coating it evenly and then transfer to a parchment-lined baking sheet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flatten the ball lightly with your fingers. (If you like, you can sprinkle a bit of additional sugar atop the cookie.) Repeat until you’ve gone through all of the dough (you may need to bake them in few batches).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 11 minutes, until the edges are set but the center remains soft.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow to cool on the baking sheet for an additional minute or so and then transfer to a rack to cool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/soft-ginger-cookies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/soft-ginger-cookies.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>desserts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pumpkin Pancakes</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;dry-mix&quot;&gt;Dry mix:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons light brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon baking powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon baking soda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ teaspoon kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons pumpkin pie spice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;wet-mix&quot;&gt;Wet mix:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup buttermilk, shaken&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large egg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup pumpkin puree&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons unsalted butter, melted and cooled slightly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a medium bowl, mix together flours, brown sugar, baking powder,
baking soda, salt, and spice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a measuring cup, measure out the buttermilk. Add the egg,
pumpkin puree, and melted butter; beat until thoroughly combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In one batch, add the wet ingredients to the dry ingredients and
mix until just combined. The batter should have some small to medium
lumps.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat up your griddle (or cast iron skillet) over medium heat and
brush with ½ tablespoon of butter. Scoop the batter, using a
tablespoon measure on to the warm skillet. Cook for 2-3 minutes, until
small bubbles form on the surface of the pancake, and then flip.
Repeat until you’re done with all the batter. Serve with pats of
butter and warm maple syrup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/pumpkin-pancakes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/pumpkin-pancakes.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creamy Mashed Cauliflower</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 (16-ounce) packages riced cauliflower, or 1 large head cauliflower&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(about 3 pounds)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cups water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finely chop the cauliflower (for whole cauliflower only). Halve
the cauliflower through the stem. Cut a “V” shape around the core to
remove the core from each half. Finely chop the cauliflower. The
smaller the pieces, the faster the cauliflower will cook and the
creamier the finished dish will be.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sauté the cauliflower. Melt the butter in a 4-quart pot over
medium-high heat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the cauliflower and sauté, stirring regularly,
until the cauliflower has lightened in color, 3 to 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Boil until tender. Add the water and salt and bring to a boil.
Cover and cook until the cauliflower is tender, about 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reserve the cooking liquid, then drain. Reserve ¼ cup of the
cooking liquid. Drain the cauliflower.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mash or purée. Place the drained cauliflower and reserved cooking
liquid back in the pot. Blend using an immersion blender to desired
consistency. Serve hot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/creamy-mashed-cauliflower.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/creamy-mashed-cauliflower.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Angel Food Cupcakes</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;for-the-cupcakes&quot;&gt;For the Cupcakes&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;½ cup + 6 tablespoons granulated sugar
1/8 teaspoon salt
½ cup cake flour, sifted
6 large egg whites, at room temperature
8 teaspoons warm water
½ teaspoon vanilla extract
¾ teaspoons cream of tartar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;for-the-coconut-cream&quot;&gt;For the Coconut Cream&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 14-ounce can coconut cream (from Trader Joe’s) or full fat coconut milk, chilled in the refrigerator overnight&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2-3 tablespoons superfine sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon pure vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;for-the-cupcakes-1&quot;&gt;For the Cupcakes&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the bowl of a food processor, fitted with the blade attachment, grind sugar for about 2 minutes.  This will help create a super fine sugar that will be better absorbed into the egg whites.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place half of the sugar in a small bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large bowl, sift together the remaining sugar, salt, and cake flour.  Set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the bowl of an electric stand mixer, fitted with a whisk attachment, beat together the egg whites, water, extract, and cream of tartar medium speed.  If you’re worried that the cream of tartar is too chunky don’t worry, it’ll smooth itself out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beat on medium high, gradually adding the sugar from the small bowl, until medium (not stiff) peaks form.  The meringue will hold a trail of the beaters through it, be glossy, and won’t be overly foamy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove the bowl from the mixer and sift in one quarter of the flour and sugar mixture.  Fold with a spatula.  Try to avoid stirring the mixture too much.  Instead, sweep the egg whites from the bottom of the bowl to the top, incorporating the flour.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add flour mixture in three more batches.  Fold until thoroughly combine, but don’t overmix or deflate the egg whites.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spoon batter into ungreased cupcake pan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 18-20 minutes, or until a skewer inserted in the cake comes out clean.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;for-the-coconut-cream-1&quot;&gt;For the Coconut Cream&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large bowl beat together coconut cream, sugar, and vanilla extract until it holds soft peaks. If you’re using coconut milk, first scrape off all of the coconut cream from the top of the can (the coconut water is great for smoothies!).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beat the cream with the sugar and vanilla. Soft peaks will appear after about 5 minutes. Do not overbeat! If you do, put back in the refrigerator for ~30 minutes, then try again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/angel-food-cupcakes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/angel-food-cupcakes.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>desserts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mushroom Barley Soup</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ½ cups boiling water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ounce dried porcini mushrooms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 tablespoons (½ stick) unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 medium onion, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 medium stalks celery, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 medium carrots, peeled and diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ teaspoon freshly ground black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup pearled barley&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12 ounces cremini mushrooms, stems removed and cut into ¼-inch-thick slices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 cups low-sodium vegetable broth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the water and porcinis in a medium heatproof bowl; set aside to soak.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Melt the butter in a Dutch oven or large pot over medium heat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the onion, celery, carrots, salt, and pepper. Cook, stirring occasionally, until the vegetables are soft and tender, about 8 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the barley and cook, stirring occasionally, until lightly toasted, about 3 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the flour, stir so it coats the barley and vegetables, and cook for 2 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the porcini mushrooms and their soaking liquid (avoid any grit at the bottom of the bowl), cremini mushrooms, and vegetable broth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring to a boil, then reduce the heat and simmer until the barley is tender, 20 to 25 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/mushroom-barley-soup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/mushroom-barley-soup.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spicy Tomato and Shrimp Soup</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large onion, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Freshly ground black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 cloves garlic, minced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ teaspoon red pepper flakes, plus more as needed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8 cups unsalted chicken broth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cups dry ditalini pasta&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ½ pounds uncooked peeled and deveined medium shrimp&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup loosely packed fresh basil leaves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat the oil in a 5-quart or larger Dutch oven over medium-high heat until shimmering.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the onion, season with salt and pepper, and sauté until translucent and softened, about 5 minutes. Add the garlic and pepper flakes and sauté until fragrant, about 1 minute more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the tomato paste and sauté until the paste has deepened in color, about 2 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stir in the chicken broth. Bring to a boil, then reduce the heat to low to simmer uncovered for 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the pasta and continue to simmer until it’s al dente, about 10 minutes or according to package instructions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Taste and season the soup with salt, pepper, and red pepper flakes as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stir in the shrimp and simmer until they are pink and opaque, 3 to 4 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinly slice the basil and serve the soup immediately, as it does not keep well, with basil sprinkled over each bowl.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/spicy-tomato-shrimp-soup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/spicy-tomato-shrimp-soup.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chicken Taco Soup</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 medium yellow onion, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cloves garlic, minced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon chili powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon ground cumin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons paprika&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons dried oregano&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ teaspoon freshly ground black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 cups (32 ounces) low-sodium chicken broth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 (15-ounce) can black beans, drained and rinsed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 (15-ounce) can diced tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 pound boneless, skinless chicken breasts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup fresh or frozen corn kernels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;for-serving-optional&quot;&gt;For serving (optional):&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 medium scallions, thinly sliced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup shredded sharp cheddar cheese&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup crushed tortilla chips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat the oil in a large Dutch oven over medium heat until shimmering.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the onion and garlic, and cook, stirring occasionally, until tender, about 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the chili powder, cumin, paprika, oregano, salt, and pepper, and cook until fragrant, about 1 minute.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the broth, beans, and tomatoes, then stir to combine.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the chicken and bring to a boil.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reduce the heat to maintain a simmer, and simmer until the chicken is cooked through and registers an internal temperature of 165℉, 10 to 14 minutes, depending on the thickness of the chicken.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer the chicken breasts to a cutting board. Shred the meat with two forks, then return the chicken to the pot.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stir in the corn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve topped with the scallions, cheese, and tortilla chips if desired.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/chicken-taco-soup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/chicken-taco-soup.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Farmer's Market Curry</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 14 oz can coconut milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 medium carrot, cut into rounads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 medium onion, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 medium butternut squash, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 medium purple potatoes, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cloves garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;basil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup vegetable stock&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon curry powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h5&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/farmers-market-curry.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/farmers-market-curry.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>to-make</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
